Helen Taylor

Contact Details

Flat 4 169 Anerley Road London SE20 8EF

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/helen-taylor-fsd

Junior Full Stack Software Developer

Full stack developer who is currently completing a diploma in software development with the Code Institute. I'm an accomplished negotiator and manager with many years of experience within the travel industry and am now seeking a new opportunity within the software engineering sector in which I can showcase and develop my skills.

Technical Skills

Frontend: HTML, JavaScript, CSS

Backend: Python

Frameworks: Flask, Bootstrap

Source control: Git

Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook

Google sheets, Gmail

Projects

Finding Pluto

An educational game to teach children about the solar system:

Technologies used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS Live link: https://belt26.github.io/Finding-Pluto/

Github repository: https://github.com/BelT26/Finding-Pluto

Redundancy Calculator

A terminal based programme which allows users to log in either as an employee to calculate their redundancy payment and submit an application, or as a member of HR to view, approve and reject applications.

Technologies used: Python, Google Sheets

Live link: https://mtl-redundancy-calculator.herokuapp.com/

Github repository: https://github.com/BelT26/RedundancyCalculator

Tie-Ups

A static website designed to showcase a range of eco-friendly Italian belts

Technologies used: HTML, CSS

Live link: https://belt26.github.io/tie-ups-uk/

Github repository: https://github.com/BelT26/tie-ups-uk

.....

Education

- Code Institute: Diploma in Full Stack Software Development (current)
- University of Birmingham: BA Honours degree in Italian and French

*

Work Experience

June 2016 - Present & October 2009 - August 2015

Senior Contracts Manager, Miki Travel Ltd

Responsible for negotiating the hotel contracts for both groups and individual travellers in Italy and Germany, building and maintaining successful relationships with suppliers and managing the locally based contractors in the Rome office.

Key Achievements

- Sourced and contracted the top selling FIT hotel for Miki Travel
- Trebled the number of room nights in Eastern Sicily

September 2015 - June 2016

Contracts Manager, Thomas Cook UK

Renewed and improved existing agreements and sourced new partners in Italy for the newly launched Thomas Cook City Escapes programme

Key Achievements

- Increased average commission levels for contracts by 3%
- Established contracts with 50 new suppliers within the first 3 months

April 2008 - September 2009

Regional Contracts Manager, Citalia Holidays

Responsible for renewing contracts, negotiating special offers and marketing promotions and managing supplier relationships.

Key achievements

- Successfully renegotiated over 90% of contracts following the onset of the financial crisis
- Surpassed targets for increasing brochure contributions and negotiating extra revenue for marketing campaigns.

November 2007- March 2008

Worked on temporary assignments for ROS Recruitment.

January 2006 - October 2007

Contracts/Product Manager, International Leisure Group, Italy

April 2004-December 2005

Contracts Executive, First Choice Holidays Ltd

November 1998-April 2004

Overseas Administration Supervisor, First Choice Holidays Ltd

Certifications

- CMI Level 5 Certificate in Management and Leadership
- ❖ ITTT TEFL Certificate
- ❖ NEB certificate in Supervisory Management (Introductory Level)

.....

Languages

- ❖ Fluent Italian
- ❖ Good working knowledge of German and French
- * Basic Croatian and Spanish

.....

Other Achievements

Raised over £2000 for research into dementia by running the 2019 London Marathon and organising fund raising events $\frac{1}{2}$